# SAFKAT HASIN ALAVI

**Github:** https://github.com/pratchad17 | **Website:** https://pratchad17.github.io/safkat-porfolilo | **LinkedIn:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/safkat-hasin-alavi-b68270184/ | **Medium:** https://www.medium.com/@pratchad.alavi

**Location:** 11/13 Block-C, Tazmahalroad, Mohammadpur, Dhaka-1207 **Email:** Pratchad.alavi@gmail.com | **Mobile:** +8801758190057

# **PROFESSIONAL STATEMENT**

To pursue a highly challenging career in the IT sector and work closely with a team of highly experienced professionals where my creative initiative, ideas and genuine enthusiasm would allow me to progress. I am highly skilled in front-end web development with over **2 years of experience** in **HTML, CSS, SCSS, JavaScript, WordPress and Appfarm**. I have knowledge of popular frameworks such as **React Js** and good experience working in multiple environments. I am very much capable of taking ownership and doing my work passionately and honestly.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages : JavaScript, Java, HTML, CSS, SCSS

**Frameworks** : React.js , Bootstrap, Tailwind, Express, Node.js

Libraries : React Router

Databases : MongoDB, MySQL

**Dev Tools** : Visual Studio Code, Git, Githab, Figma, Adobe Illustrator

**CMS** : WordPress, WordPress Elementor

**Development Plat-:** Appfarm

form

Framework : Storybook

**Agonostic Tool** 

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Associate UI Engineer BRAIN Station-23

Sept 2021 - Present

8th Floor, 2 Bir Uttam AK Khandakar Road, Dhaka 1212, Bangladesh

- Designed and developed dynamic and responsive websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, WordPress and Appfarm
- Worked in different environment like: Moodle, Adobe Express Manager

## **VOLUNTARY EXPERIENCE**

# **Campus Ambassador of BASIS Student Forum**

Jan 2019 - April 2021

BASIS Student Forum

Senior Executive of BRAC University Computer Club

Jan 2018 – June 2021

**BUCC** 

**Executive of BRAC University Robotics Club** 

Jan 2018- Jan2021

ROBU

Vice President of Dhaka City College Science Club

Jan 2015 - March 2016

DCCSC

**RCY of Red Crescent** 

Noakhali Red Crescent Unit

Jan 2012- Present

#### **EDUCATION**

### **BRAC UNIVERSITY**

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

66 Mohakhali, Dhaka-1212, Bangladesh Jan 2017 – Sept-2021

# **Dhaka City College**

Higher Secondary School Certificate

Road No. 2 Dhanmondi, Dhaka-1205, Bangladesh Aug 2014– May 2016

Noakhali Zilla School

Secondary School Certificate

Maijdeecourt, Shadar, Noakhali, Bangladesh Jan 2013 – Jan-2014 Project 1 QBIG https://qbig.appfarm.app

- \* Full-stack Development using Appfarm and JavaScript
- \* It's a Norwegian Project
- \* Duration: April 2023 Present

Project 2 SKATZOHEROS https://skatzoheros.chalvantzis.com/

- \* Theme development and full website development
- \* Technology Used: WordPress and Elementor

#### **Project 3**

#### LEADRS (USA Government project)

- \* UI development, Some component Development
- \* Technology Used: **HTML**, **CSS**, **Java Script**

Project 4 ABBVIE SITEGEN

- \* Front-end development, Component Development
- \* Technology Used: AEM, Storybook, React, Java Script, HTML, CSS, SASS

Project 5 Brain Station-23 https://brainstation-23.com

- \* UI support, Some Page Development
- \* Technology Used: WordPress, Elementor

Project 6 MAGIC BAULIANA https://magicbauliana.com.bd/

- \* Development
- \* Technology Used: WordPress, Elementor

# Project 7

#### ALLERGON-INTERACTIVE-COURSE

- \* Creating markup and UI design. It is a moodle based project.
- \* Project Duration: 20 Oct,2021- Dec 2021

Publication Conversion of Bengali speech to text using long short-term memory(LSTM)

http://hdl.handle.net/10361/15435

## **CERTIFICATIONS AND ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Advanced Web development Certificate
- 3rd Position in the poster competition of the National Environment Olympiad
- Graphics design Certificate
- Amateur Radio Service Certificate
- 3rd in Science Fair 2013 (Chittagong division)
- 1st position in Poster presentation in Spectra-Intra BRACU Tech Fest
- Animated Flim Making
- 10th National rover moot and 5th National comodeca (Scout)
- 12 National RCY Camp (Red Crescent)
- · Nationally 1st in Essay Competition
- 3rd in Noakhali Math Olympiad
- Firmware Development
- Project presentation (Basis Soft Expo)
- 2nd Runner up, Sailor Champions of the Earth Season 3
- Government Scholarship in Primary (class 5)
- Government Scholarship in Junior School Certificate(JSC) (class 8)
- Government Scholarship in Secondary School Certificate (SSC) (class 10)
- 2nd round, Esho Robot Banai Channel i (2019)